Hey guys, how's it going?
We are now on version 0.5 of Pyqttyai and
I'll try to be really quick here so as not to
extend this video too much.
I made documentation for it explaining
that it stands for Python, QT, TTY, and AI, the latter being
artificial intelligence, and this version 0.5
is bringing a first model which is
to perform audio transcription.
So here I made a brief summary of how
the idea started, then a roadmap here of
how the versions evolved, a
description of all these versions, there are the
videos here, each version has its video in
English, Portuguese, and it has subtitles too.
and here later between version 0.4 and 0.5,
I made a gap here, I called it, of several
studies, of various AI models, what can
run on the machine, what cannot, what
has to be in the cloud, what can be done
right now, what I had to leave for later.
So, for later ended up being now
an intelligence using NLP, Natural
Language Processing, and an AI model
to perform audio transcription.
And in version 0.6, I have already done some tests,
an AI model that can read the image,
interpret what you request based
on that image, and deliver the code
ready for you to drop
into a switch or a router.
Ready?
Of course you have to review it first, right?
But in the next version, that is what is coming up.
I'm going to put this documentation and the
software on my GitHub, then I will
put it here and you will be able to
access, download, test...
Going back here to EVE, I will click here on
router 20, it will call the software,
and it will open Pyqttyai here and will load
this Whisper model that does the
transcription.
It loaded here the model
version 3 turbo on my video card.
It is a modest video card, it has 2GB, the
model took up practically 1.5GB.
and here is the Intel video card, which
is built into the processor.
So here I am going to do the audio
transcription using the
NVIDIA video card.
Now the button bar here, the
taskbar here got a microphone.
Just to give you an idea of what can be
done, I'll click here to show you.
Cisco initial configuration, Hostname
router20, Username Cisco, Password, Class.
Now it will do the transcription, using
my video card.
So if I look here, it was here
at 100% processing, it did the
processing and delivered a ready code here,
which is the initial Cisco configuration.
So here it does a natural language
processing, where it will take
through regular expressions, I
put it here.
so here is where it will pick up a
word or keywords and from them
capture in your speech or in the text that is
there, capture some information and generate
a new text, in this case it generated an
initial code for a Cisco router.
So if I am to analyze here, this
generated code, it got router 20, the
router 20, Cisco and class as password.
So if I search here in this
generated code, I will see router 20 here
in a few places.
I will see the password class, here, here, here
too, and I will see the user, here it put
"namecisco", why?
It is something I will even have to fix, it
will take everything between user and
password, remove the characters that are not
allowed and compose the username,
but I only wanted "cisco", what can I
do?
Select it, CTRL+SHIFT+F, I'll change the
"namecisco" to just "cisco".
Ok, it changed already.
So it also has this feature of
CTRL+SHIFT+F, to search, to do a
replace, so if I search here,
for example, the word pass, it repeats
eight times here in this text.
So here I already have an initial Cisco
configuration code, where it
configures line, password, everything and I can
send it, I will connect here to my router
in EVE, it was there on router 20, I can
send this script there to that router.
let me see if it is here, if it is loaded, the
time here I'll speed up a bit to 100 ms
and send the script.
So here it
is sending the entire script already, it is
working, we notice that
it gave some minor errors up there
Let's see...
here, because here I gave the command that the
password must be a minimum of 10 digits,
10 characters and the class password is less.
what can I do?
I can even delete this here, come here and
let's fix it right here, user is Cisco,
password class with more characters, for
example, and I will send this new one, I hit
CTRL+SHIFT+A, it will read this line and will
generate that code again down here.
so I could be speaking again, then
it will take my speech and do
this, or I come to a line that has, that
is already written here, hit CTRL+SHIFT+A,
it will check if it matches any of these
rules that are already set up here.
So here it is, I'm going to send this
script again, it's all ready now, now
you see that there is no error, had an error,
generated SSH key, activated the SSH key, ok.
So here it already does it with a simple
voice command here, it already did the entire
initial Cisco configuration code here.
talking now about the AI models, here I
made a playground where you can pick the
Faster-Whisper models, OpenVINO,
OpenVINO-GenAI and Cloud.
Here we were already using this
NVIDIA CUDA language, from the GPU and here
is OpenVINO, it does
it will perform a transcription of the
code that is for the NVIDIA GPU to
the Intel GPU, it takes a long time, it's not here
because I tested it and saw how it works,
it works well, but I don't advise using it
because of this delay, better to use this
OpenVINO-GenAI which is already a repository, if
I come here,
OpenVINO has this repository, all the
models are already here already transcribed
from NVIDIA to Intel, so you don't
have to spend memory, which is a lot of
memory, minimum 16GB to perform a
transcription and use the model, while
using the one already
transcribed takes very little, if we go very little compared to
those 16GB.
I even did a survey here of the
Faster-Whisper models, for each model
size it has, I did the OpenVINO one that
downloads, from OpenAI and then transcribes
this code, this model for Intel and here
the models already coded for Intel,
so
and, for you to see the sizes here, if
we take the turbo here, it is at
1.6, so instead of 16GB to do all
this processing of this model to
get to this other one here, which I will
have to have about 16GB available there, I already
grab it straight from here, so it's not worth
working here, it's really just a
proof of concept.
So if I use this one here,
since I already downloaded it, it will just load, it will
load very fast, about 3 seconds, it
loads and I can click here to
test, testing the transcription
using the Intel GPU, it will be
used, I will see here in btop the usage of this
GPU, it would be GPU 1, to perform the
transcription of this audio.
So now, you see that the GPU hit
100% there and I see what happened this
processing, it already delivered me here an
audio transcription, everything that was
spoken there, it transcribed, it's here,
here it does a statistic, so 18
seconds of audio, delivered to me in 7
seconds,
a speed of two and a half times.
The NVIDIA GPU tends to be a little bit
faster, it loads faster here,
we will see, it loads faster, a
little bit faster.
doing a new test now of
audio transcription using the
NVIDIA GPU.
Now it will do this
transcription, we will see here an audio
of 10, delivered in 4, resulted in two and a
half times, basically the same thing, there's not
much difference.
the NVIDIA one tends to be a little bit
faster, but it depends on the processing and
everything that's running there at the moment.
And there is the cloud. In the cloud I can test
various clouds here, I can be including,
I included these for me to test.
Gemini
is not worth it, because Gemini doesn't
transcribe it interprets what you are
saying and returns it to you, it takes time, it takes a while like this:
it will basically take your time if
you spoke for 10 seconds, you will wait more than
10 seconds there for it to return to you.
Fireworks
and Groq return it to you within 1 or 2 seconds.
Fireworks AI, it uses GPU and
Groq a company that developed
a proprietary processor, an LPU, for
Language Processing Unit, so it is neither CPU
nor GPU, it is an LPU and it is for
AI processing with natural language, very fast,
very fast indeed.
So let's test Fireworks here first,
load, I will connect over there on
Fireworks, it is asking for the key, I will come
here,
Fireworks, Hugging Face which is a cloud,
I could be subscribing to it too, it
will give me the credits, the prices, it doesn't
pay off.
Fireworks is also paid, a tenth of a
cent per minute, in Brazilian Reais it would be half
a cent per minute, so one hour of
audio would be around, 60 minutes, it would be around
30 cents.
it is not very cheap, it works well, very
cheap, fast, however Groq is free,
but let's test it here just to show that
it works, I will generate a test API here,
oops, later I will delete this key guys,
copy here, throw it here, ok,
connected to my key, great.
Now I'm going to run an audio transcription
test using this cloud from
Fireworks AI and really analyze the
speed with which it can
deliver an audio transcription to me,
remembering that this audio will be recorded
here, being transmitted there to the cloud,
there it will be transcribed, trans...
transcribed and...
and the text returned to me.
Now we are going to see the speed here,
in 2 seconds it delivered to me almost 30
seconds of audio, and the transcription is very
good here, very well done, smooth, in
several languages, if we look here
there are 100 languages, 99 languages, I don't remember,
something around 100 different
languages.
and I can speak mixed, I can speak
part Portuguese, part English, but you
saw the Fireworks time here, now
we are going to test with Groq.
Let's go generate a Groq key.
I will generate a Groq test key,
copy, paste here, about the GPU here,
my GPU here,
here it has 2GB, on Nvidia, but the model
fits within these 2GB, the driver already uses
a tiny bit, but if I put it here
we see...
and after doing the gpu, if I load the
model here, we see that it will be
using here more or less 1.5 GB, it already had
0.3 GB, so 1.1 GB here, so,
transcribes... the audio transcription,
using the gpu is also very smooth,
it works well, you see here that it is not
working, it's just recording, now it will
process my audio, hit 100%, here we
see that it is processing, it was very
fast, processed locally, delivered 13
seconds in 5 seconds, now on Groq,
Connect to it.
Now let's do a test with Groq,
to see if it really has all that
speed that they say they are capable
of delivering, doing now a transcription
of an audio around 15 seconds and
analyzing how long it takes them,
not 15 right, much more, about 25 seconds it
will be, to see the time it manages to
deliver to me,
and the quality of this transcription.
It is very fast, Groq is very fast and the
transcription is basically perfect here,
hard to find a problem.
And I can speak one part in Portuguese and
I can speak other other part in English too.
So it brings here one part in
and one part in English.
So it works very
well, very fast, and I advise, if you have internet,
to use Groq, if you don't, if you have an
NVIDIA video card, you can use NVIDIA's,
otherwise the built-in Intel video card
works too, very well, quite similar to NVIDIA.
Here saving here, ok, here I will
open the workspace that was already saved here.
Here it is already mapped, just like the last video
as I click here it goes to the router,
I click here, it connects to all of them, here it disconnects
from all of them there in EVE, connected to all.
And here for you to have an idea now
that we can write the script without
touching anything.
Let's go?
ENTER
ENABLE
CONFIGURE TERMINAL, ENTER
router bgp1919, enter, bgp router-id 16.16.16.16,
ENTER.
I think I...
I think I said one extra 16 there, right?
Or it sometimes has this problem of,
what we call hallucinating and finding
things where they don't exist.
ENTER
neighbor 150.150.150.150.1, remote-as 1818
Here it missed a space, ENTER
And then as I had said there in the rules
there is also IPv6 right so if I say
here IPv6, IPv6 192.168.10.acad.café.2.2.3
So you can see that, as I said,
IPv6, it understands that after this an IPv6 will come
So I said several things and it already came
in this format.
If I don't say IPv6, just to give
us an idea, 192.168.10.acad, cafe, colon,
colon, three.
So look at what it delivers here, so
if I say IPv6 first, it goes there
and applies the rule, the IPv6 regex, and
I also implemented here a CTRL+:(;),
it also goes there and adjusts it for us,
right, if you press CTRL+., it does IPv4,
CTRL+:(;), it does IPv6.
if I hit Ctrl+-(dash) it will change the
colon to a dash and Ctrl+Shift+space
it changes it to a space.
So we can play around here very
quickly for us to
...
Be switching between IPv6 and IPv4, when
we forget.
So, imagine here, that if I have this
here, I can copy, paste, come here,
hit Ctrl+:,
and here one more colon, here IPv6
is made from that one above, and
here we can play around a bit, for
example, Activate, Delirium, Hallucination,
OK.
Activate, now it worked.
Well then, we can write a
script just by speaking, of course you
need to speak with the correct pause, say the
dash joined with the words,
words, amount of numbers and dots,
sometimes it can hallucinate a bit, but
it works well, overall it works well, we
can implant several rules, we can
write the rules here very flexibly,
the shortcuts are here, it's all
here, many shortcuts, many
features that I have already implemented.
And that's it.
Wrapping up the video here which ended
up getting a bit long, of this version 0.5
but I think it was possible to explain here at
least an introduction to the use of the microphone,
to the use of AI and it turned out really cool, it's very
complete.
Thanks, until the next version 0.6.